NIROOJEN THAMBIMUTHU

niroojen.thambimuthu@gmail.com \diamond (587)889-2376 \diamond 3839 Varsity Dr NW, Calgary, Alberta, T3A 0Z3 www.linkedin.com/in/niroojen-thambimuthu \diamond https://niroojen-thambimuthu.github.io/MyWebsite/

SUMMARY

A highly motivated Computer Scientist, with project experiences in software analysis, testing and development. Strong interpersonal and time management skills, with a proven track record of providing superior results under high pressure situations. Creative problem-solving and analytical mindset, with proficiency in documenting and learning new technologies.

QUALIFICATIONS

- Proficient in several programming languages including C#, C, HTML, Javascript, CSS, SQL, Python, Java, LaTeX, PHP, React, Node.js and Visual Basic.
- Quick learner, from personal and constructive peer feedback, and currently learning Microsoft .NET technologies such as VB.NET and VBScript.
- Strong foundation in various software practices and technologies, leading to a better understand and approach to fulfil complex solutions presented by the client.
- Exceptional interpersonal, oral and communication skills allowing me to work in single or team environments with limited supervision, obtained from projects and retail experience with clients.
- Showcased leadership, problem-solving and decision-making skills through completion of multiple occurring projects, while allocating priorities to others teammates under time pressure.
- Extensive technical written skills from software project documentations and final research reports.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science, Computer Science

September 2014 - June 2019

- University of Calgary Calgary, AB
- Course Highlights: Security, Software Development, Database Programming, Web Design, Network

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

QuickSplash Game - http://www.quicksplash.ca/

January - April 2019

University of Calgary - Calgary, AB

- Wrote a party questioning game, in a group of six, which allows multiple users to play simultaneously
- Developed front-end by layering HTML, CSS, Javascript, Bootstrap and CreateJS on top of React framework
- Utilized Node.js as Server-Side Technology and Socket.io for cookies and MongoDB implementations
- Used Agile software development principles into practices using Scrum methodology and pair programming
- Tested game dynamics using manual automation scripting to simulate different gaming sessions, and Google Developer Tools for mobile and responsiveness testing

Rental Website

September - December 2017

University of Calgary - Calgary, AB

- Created makeshift rental housing market website, in a group of 3, showcasing proficiency in using database SQL and PHP implementations
- Personally scheduled weekly meetings and communicated effectively with the team to ensure successful completion of the project
- Completed the technical documentation and manual testing of the project using Test Driven Development principles

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Password Meter Research Papers

University of Calgary - Calgary, AB

September 2017 - April 2018

- Conducted research on the effectiveness of password meters to users, resulting in a better understanding of security processes and protocols
- Worked in a group of four to collect and analyse quantitative password meter data integration from websites, including other research methods
- Reported findings through written report and presentation

CERTIFICATIONS

The Complete SQL Bootcamp

November 2019

Learned to query database and perform data analysis using SQL and PostgreSQL

Full-Stack Web Development with React Specialization

April - September 2019

- Build Web and Hybrid Mobile Solutions using React
- Front End and Server-Side Development
- Learned more on major technologies: HTML, CSS, React, Bootstrap

Google IT Support Professional Specialization

May - June 2019

- Learned basics of System Administration and IT Infrastructure Services
- Technical Support Fundamentals and IT Security

OTHER TECHNICAL SKILLS

Software & Tools	TeX-works, Visual Studio code, GitHub, Eclipse, MS Office(Word, Excel, Powerpoint)
Database	MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Relational Databases, Entity Relationship Model
Operating System	Linux, Unix, Mac OS, Microsoft Windows, iOS.
Software Practices	Object Oriented Programming (OOP), TestDriven Development(TDD),
	Agile Development, Human-Computer Interaction principles

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Service-Clerk/Cashier

September 2013 - Present

Calgary COOP - Calgary, AB

- Responsible for managing transactions, organizing store, and participating with the management to increase retail productivity
- Efficient in building and maintaining diverse customer relations and resolving customer problems, leading to increase in retail sales and customer satisfaction
- Demonstrated great leadership traits, and performed clerical tasks in a fast paced environment, while ensuring high service standards are properly followed

INTEREST

Activities	Various Sports, Biking, DIY mechanic, Driving, Reading, Logic Games, Fitness
Technology	Computers, Small Devices, Security implementations, Video Games, New Technology